<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<attacker-controls>
    <security-control>
        <id>AS1</id>
        <name>Authentication</name>
        <description>
            <point>Credentials and authentication tokens are protected with encryption in storage and transit .</point>
            <point>Protocols are resistant to brute force , dictionary , and replay attacks .</point>
            <point>Strong password policies are enforced .</point>
            <point>Trusted server authentication is used instead of SQL authentication .</point>
            <point>Passwords are stored with salted hashes .</point>
            <point>Password resets do not reveal password hints and valid usernames .</point>
            <point>Account lockouts do not result in a denial of service attack</point>
        </description>
    </security-control>
    <security-control>
        <id>AS2</id>
        <name>Authorization</name>
        <description>
            <point>Strong ACLs are used for enforcing authorized access to resources .</point>
            <point>Role-based access controls are used to restrict access to specific operations .</point>
            <point>The system follows the principle of least privilege for user and service accounts .</point>
            <point>Privilege separation is correctly configured within the presentation , business and data access
                layers
            </point>
        </description>
    </security-control>
    <security-control>
        <id>AS3</id>
        <name>Configuration Management</name>
        <description>
            <point>Standard encryption algorithms and correct key sizes are being used .</point>
            <point>Hashed message authentication codes -LRB- HMACs -RRB- are used to protect data integrity .</point>
            <point>Secrets -LRB- e.g. keys , confidential data -RRB- are cryptographically protected both in transport
                and in storage .
            </point>
            <point>Built-in secure storage is used for protecting keys .</point>
            <point>No credentials and sensitive data are sent in clear text over the wire</point>
        </description>
    </security-control>
    <security-control>
        <id>AS4</id>
        <name>Data Protection in Storage and Transit</name>
        <description>
            <point>Standard encryption algorithms and correct key sizes are being used .</point>
            <point>Hashed message authentication codes -LRB- HMACs -RRB- are used to protect data integrity .</point>
            <point>Secrets -LRB- e.g. keys , confidential data -RRB- are cryptographically protected both in transport
                and in storage .
            </point>
            <point>Built-in secure storage is used for protecting keys .</point>
            <point>No credentials and sensitive data are sent in clear text over the wire</point>
        </description>
    </security-control>
    <security-control>
        <id>AS5</id>
        <name>Data Validation / Parameter Validation</name>
        <description>
            <point>Data type , format , length , and range checks are enforced .</point>
            <point>All data sent from the client is validated .</point>
            <point>No security decision is based upon parameters -LRB- e.g. URL parameters -RRB- that can be manipulated
                .
            </point>
            <point>Input filtering via white list validation is used .</point>
            <point>Output encoding is used</point>
        </description>
    </security-control>
    <security-control>
        <id>AS6</id>
        <name>Error Handling and Exception Management</name>
        <description>
            <point>All exceptions are handled in a structured manner .</point>
            <point>Privileges are restored to the appropriate level in case of errors and exceptions .</point>
            <point>Error messages are scrubbed so that no sensitive information is revealed to the attacker</point>
        </description>
    </security-control>
    <security-control>
        <id>AS7</id>
        <name>User and Session Management</name>
        <description>
            <point>No sensitive information is stored in clear text in the cookie .</point>
            <point>The contents of the authentication cookies is encrypted .</point>
            <point>Cookies are configured to expire .</point>
            <point>Sessions are resistant to replay attacks .</point>
            <point>Secure communication channels are used to protect authentication cookies .</point>
            <point>User is forced to re-authenticate when performing critical functions .</point>
            <point>Sessions are expired at logout</point>
        </description>
    </security-control>
    <security-control>
        <id>AS8</id>
        <name>Auditing and Logging</name>
        <description>
            <point>Sensitive information -LRB- e.g. passwords , PII -RRB- is not logged .</point>
            <point>Access controls -LRB- e.g. ACLs -RRB- are enforced on log files to prevent un-authorized access .
            </point>
            <point>Integrity controls -LRB- e.g. signatures -RRB- are enforced on log files to provide non-repudiation
                .
            </point>
            <point>Log files provide for audit trail for sensitive operations and logging of key events .</point>
            <point>Auditing and logging is enabled across the tiers on multiple servers</point>
        </description>
    </security-control>
</attacker-controls>